<?xml version='1.0'?>
<mavlink>
	<include>common.xml</include>
	<messages>
		<!-- 15x messages are actuator related -->
		<message id="150" name="RUDDER_RAW">
			<description>This message encodes all of the raw rudder sensor data from the USV.</description>
			<field type="uint16_t" name="raw_position">The raw data from the position sensor, generally a potentiometer.</field>
			<field type="uint8_t" name="port_limit">Status of the rudder limit sensor, port side. 0 indicates off and 1 indicates that the limit is hit. If this sensor is inactive set to 0xFF.</field>
			<field type="uint8_t" name="center_limit">Status of the rudder limit sensor, port side. 0 indicates off and 1 indicates that the limit is hit. If this sensor is inactive set to 0xFF.</field>
			<field type="uint8_t" name="starboard_limit">Status of the rudder limit sensor, starboard side. 0 indicates off and 1 indicates that the limit is hit. If this sensor is inactive set to 0xFF.</field>
			<field type="uint16_t" name="port_limit_val">Holds the raw value that indicates the port limit in ADC units. Used for mapping the raw ADC values into real units.</field>
			<field type="uint16_t" name="starboard_limit_val">Holds the raw value that indicates the starboard limit in ADC units. Used for mapping the raw ADC values into real units.</field>
		</message>
		<!-- 16x messages are environment/physical sensor related -->
		<message id="160" name="WSO100">
			<description>Returns the raw wind/air sensor values from the WSO100.</description>
			<field type="float" name="speed">Wind speed in m/s.</field>
			<field type="float" name="direction">Wind direction in rads east from north.</field>
			<field type="float" name="temperature">Air temperature in degrees Celsius.</field>
			<field type="float" name="pressure">Air pressure in Pascals.</field>
			<field type="float" name="humidity">Air humidity in %.</field>
		</message>
		<message id="161" name="DST800">
			<description>Water-related measurements from the DST800.</description>
			<field type="float" name="speed">Water speed in m/s.</field>
			<field type="float" name="temperature">Water temperature in degrees Celsius.</field>
			<field type="float" name="depth">Water depth in m (DST800 range is 100m). Invalid measurements are 0.0.</field>
		</message>
		<message id="162" name="REVO_GS">
			<description>Attitude measurements from the Revolution GS compass.</description>
			<field type="float" name="heading">Heading in degrees eastward from north</field>
			<field type="uint8_t" name="mag_status">Magnetometer status</field>
			<field type="float" name="pitch">Pitch angle in degrees.</field>
			<field type="uint8_t" name="pitch_status">Pitch status</field>
			<field type="float" name="roll">Roll angle in degrees.</field>
			<field type="uint8_t" name="roll_status">Roll status</field>
			<field type="float" name="dip">Dip angle in degrees.</field>
			<field type="uint16_t" name="mag_horiz_comp">Horizontal component of the earth's magnetic field.</field>
		</message>
		<message id="163" name="GPS200">
			<description>Various interesting fields from the GPS200 CAN stream. This will likely be obsolete if/when a CAN datalogger becomes available.</description>
			<field type="float" name="magnetic_variation">Magnetic variation for the current GPS location. In units of degrees.</field>
		</message>
		<message id="164" name="DSP3000">
			<description>The z rotation rate as reported by the KVH DSP-3000 gyro.</description>
			<field type="float" name="z_rate">Z-axis rotation rate in rads/s, clockwise positive.</field>
		</message>
		<!-- 17x messages are system/status messages -->
		<message id="171" name="BASIC_STATE">
			<description>This message holds all values of interest for a basic analysis of the autopilot performance.</description>
			<field type="float" name="commanded_auto_rudder_angle">This is the rudder angle command as commanded by the onboard autonomous controller. It's in milliradians where positive indicates port-side.</field>
			<field type="float" name="commanded_primary_rudder_angle">This is the rudder angle command as commanded by the primary manual controller. It's in milliradians where positive indicates port-side.</field>
			<field type="float" name="commanded_secondary_rudder_angle">This is the rudder angle command as commanded by the secondary/emergency manual controller. It's in milliradians where positive indicates port-side.</field>
			<field type="float" name="rudder_angle">The interpreted rudder angle in radians.</field>
			<field type="int16_t" name="commanded_auto_throttle">This is the throttle command as commanded by the onboard autonomous controller. It's in units of 1/1023*100% of max current and positive values propel the vehicle forward.</field>
			<field type="int16_t" name="commanded_primary_throttle">This is the throttle command as commanded by the primary manual controller. It's in units of 1/1023*100% of max current and positive values propel the vehicle forward.</field>
			<field type="int16_t" name="commanded_secondary_throttle">This is the throttle command as commanded by the secondary/emergency manual controller. It's in units of 1/1023*100% of max current and positive values propel the vehicle forward.</field>
			<field type="int16_t" name="prop_speed">Propeller speed, positive values mean the vessel will be propelled forward. Units are in RPM.</field>
			<field type="float" name="a_cmd">This is the lateral acceleration as commanded by the onboard L2+ controller. Units are in m/s^2.</field>
			<field type="float" name="L2_north">North-coordinate of the L2 vector in mm.</field>
			<field type="float" name="L2_east">East-coordinate of the L2 vector in mm.</field>
		</message>
		<message id="172" name="MAIN_POWER">
			<description>Displays the voltage level and power draw of the main battery.</description>
			<field type="uint16_t" name="voltage">The current main battery rail voltage. In units of 0.01V.</field>
			<field type="uint16_t" name="current_draw">The current being drawn from the main battery bank. In units of 0.1A.</field>
		</message>
		<message id="173" name="NODE_STATUS">
			<description>Display the status information of every node in the network.</description>
			<field type="uint16_t" name="hil_status">Status bitfield for the HIL node. Consult HilNode.h for details.</field>
			<field type="uint16_t" name="hil_errors">Reset bitfield for the HIL node. Consult HilNode.h for details.</field>
			<field type="int8_t" name="hil_temp">The onboard temperature of the HIL node in units of degrees Celsius. INT8_MAX if unmeasured/invalid.</field>
			<field type="uint8_t" name="hil_load">The onboard CPU load of the HIL node in units of 1%. UINT8_MAX if unmeasured/invalid.</field>
			<field type="uint8_t" name="hil_voltage">The onboard unregulated voltage of the HIL node in units of .1V. UINT8_MAX if unmeasured/invalid.</field>
			<field type="uint16_t" name="imu_status">Status bitfield for the imu node. Consult ImuNode.h for details.</field>
			<field type="uint16_t" name="imu_errors">Reset bitfield for the imu node. Consult ImutNode.h for details.</field>
			<field type="int8_t" name="imu_temp">The onboard temperature of the imu node in units of degrees Celsius. INT8_MAX if unmeasured/invalid.</field>
			<field type="uint8_t" name="imu_load">The onboard CPU load of the imu node in units of 1%. UINT8_MAX if unmeasured/invalid.</field>
			<field type="uint8_t" name="imu_voltage">The onboard unregulated voltage of the IMU node in units of .1V. UINT8_MAX if unmeasured/invalid.</field>
			<field type="uint16_t" name="power_status">Status bitfield for the power node. Consult PowerNode.h for details.</field>
			<field type="uint16_t" name="power_errors">Reset bitfield for the power node. Consult PowerNode.h for details.</field>
			<field type="int8_t" name="power_temp">The onboard temperature of the power node in units of degrees Celsius. INT8_MAX if unmeasured/invalid.</field>
			<field type="uint8_t" name="power_load">The onboard CPU load of the power node in units of 1%. UINT8_MAX if unmeasured/invalid.</field>
			<field type="uint8_t" name="power_voltage">The onboard unregulated voltage of the power node in units of .1V. UINT8_MAX if unmeasured/invalid.</field>
			<field type="uint16_t" name="primary_status">Status bitfield for the Primary Node. Consult PrimaryNode.h for details.</field>
			<field type="uint16_t" name="primary_errors">Reset bitfield for the Primary Node. Consult PrimaryNode.h for details.</field>
			<field type="int8_t" name="primary_temp">The onboard temperature of the primary node in units of degrees Celsius. INT8_MAX if unmeasured/invalid.</field>
			<field type="uint8_t" name="primary_load">The onboard CPU load of the primary node in units of 1%. UINT8_MAX if unmeasured/invalid.</field>
			<field type="uint8_t" name="primary_voltage">The onboard unregulated voltage of the primary node in units of .1V. UINT8_MAX if unmeasured/invalid.</field>
			<field type="uint16_t" name="rc_status">Status bitfield for the RC node. Consult RcNode.h for details.</field>
			<field type="uint16_t" name="rc_errors">Reset bitfield for the RC node. Consult RcNode.h for details.</field>
			<field type="int8_t" name="rc_temp">The onboard temperature of the RC node in units of degrees Celsius. INT8_MAX if unmeasured/invalid.</field>
			<field type="uint8_t" name="rc_load">The onboard CPU load of the RC node in units of 1%. UINT8_MAX if unmeasured/invalid.</field>
			<field type="uint8_t" name="rc_voltage">The onboard unregulated voltage of the RC node in units of .1V. UINT8_MAX if unmeasured/invalid.</field>
			<field type="uint16_t" name="rudder_status">Status bitfield for the rudder node. Consult RudderNode.h for details.</field>
			<field type="uint16_t" name="rudder_errors">Reset bitfield for the rudder node. Consult RudderNode.h for details.</field>
			<field type="int8_t" name="rudder_temp">The onboard temperature of the rudder node in units of degrees Celsius. INT8_MAX if unmeasured/invalid.</field>
			<field type="uint8_t" name="rudder_load">The onboard CPU load of the rudder node in units of 1%. UINT8_MAX if unmeasured/invalid.</field>
			<field type="uint8_t" name="rudder_voltage">The onboard unregulated voltage of the rudder node in units of .1V. UINT8_MAX if unmeasured/invalid.</field>
		</message>
		<message id="174" name="WAYPOINT_STATUS">
			<description>Shows the parameters for the last mission and the next mission. Useful for analyzing where the vessel should have been after a test.</description>
			<field type="float" name="last_wp_lat">The latitude of the last waypoint.</field>
			<field type="float" name="last_wp_lon">The longitude of the last waypoint.</field>
			<field type="float" name="last_wp_north">The north component of the local coordinates of the last waypoint.</field>
			<field type="float" name="last_wp_east">The east component of the local coordinates of the last waypoint.</field>
			<field type="float" name="next_wp_lat">The latitude of the next waypoint.</field>
			<field type="float" name="next_wp_lon">The longitude of the next waypoint.</field>
			<field type="float" name="next_wp_north">The north component of the local coordinates of the next waypoint.</field>
			<field type="float" name="next_wp_east">The east component of the local coordinates of the next waypoint.</field>
		</message>
	</messages>
</mavlink>
